Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpurohit, I am
MBA Finance of Founder Family First Financial Services and have been working in the corporate sector for 13 years and
today I am presenting to you I Protect
Smart Term Plan from ICIC Prudential which has a life continuation option. This has happened where you
can get a discount up to 30 years, here you can also take the death benefit together, you
can also take it in the income term of 10 years, you can also select the option for 20 years,
you can get it for 30 years. You can also take the option of death benefit as income.
You can take half the death benefit at once and you can take the remaining amount as income also,
where you will get different discounts, so let us understand. How this discount will work is in the video.
If you like the video, then subscribe to my YouTube channel Anil Rajpurohit fffs
and also share this video with as many people as possible so that they
can also get the benefit of this discount. See what is the objective of a term insurance?
The objective of term insurance is that the earning person in the house is the bread and butter winner. If something happens to
him tomorrow, how will the house run? Where will the income come from? For example,
a person is 35 years old and his life span is 2 or 5 years. If
something happens to those who have been earning for 35 years, then when the child grows up to 2-5 years and turns 25,
after 20 years, when he starts earning, then the house will start earning , how will
the house run till then? Pay term life insurance is very useful where you
get a huge amount for the family and it is very
useful in running the household, in meeting the household expenses, in children's education, in marriage, i.e. in the wife and daily expenses of the family.
For example, one He is a 35 year old person, he pays the premium for 10 years and
he takes the policy term of 30 years i.e. he needs insurance cover till he turns 65 years of age
and he has kept the insurance cover worth ₹ Crore, which I
Let me try to explain you in the example, I have
taken a further option of Rs 1 crore 50 lakh, here you will get three options, first pay the premium for 10 years, the policy will last for
30 years, second option is given premium, pay the premium for 30 years, the
policy will last for 30 years and the third. The option has been given to pay the premium till you turn 60. The policy
will last for 30 years. If the customer is 35 years old then the first option has been given that if the customer dies
then the nominee will get the entire Rs 2 crores at once and the policy will be closed. So if
you take two crores together then your premium in 10 pay will be
Rs 63340, in regular pay your premium will be
Rs 9840 and if you take till Rs 60, you
will get a premium of Rs 3663 but if you take this death option in installments then you will get monthly
income . You start taking it in the form that for your nominee you have decided that
in case of death, instead of getting ₹ crore rupees together, my nominee
will get ₹ 666666 every month for the next 10 years, ₹
66000 per month for the next 10 years. If you get a nominee for one year then
you will get a discount of Rs 15. If you select the option of income for 20 years
then you will get a discount of Rs 20. If you select the option of monthly income for 30 years
then you will get a discount of Rs 30. Now let's see, at the discount of Rs 15, your
premium will start coming to Rs 53 instead of Rs 63, in regular pay the premium will be Rs 25,000 instead of Rs 29,000
and in Pay Rs 60, the premium will be Rs 28,000 instead of Rs 33,000. Now if you
take it for 20 years, I have income for 20 years to the nominee. In that case you
are getting a premium of 50000 before 63 and in regular pay you are getting a premium of 23000
and at 60 you are getting a premium of 26 and if you decide that in the next
If the nominee keeps getting income every month for 30 years , then you will get a discount on Rs. 30 i.e.
Rs. 44,338. After increasing the premium for 10 years, the insurance cover of Rs. 2 crore will last for the next 30 years and
whenever there is a death, the nominee will get Rs. 55,556 per month for the next 30 years. Will continue to receive for a year.
Now if you decide and select another option that out of the two crores, the
nominee should get one crore immediately as a big amount and the remaining one
crore will be received in monthly instalments, then there You can see from the back that you
have a discount of 10% on 75% and up to 15% if you want to take income for 10 years, if you want to
take income for 20 years or if you want to take income for 30 years then here also
you will get the discount. You will see different premium options, so if you
want to take a big lump sum or if you feel that an income is necessary for my family, in case
something happens to me tomorrow and you are not able to afford a big
premium. You can select this installment option to get death benefit.
The option available to the nominees is that they can select 10 years, 20 years or 30 years,
where the premium will also be reduced, now everything has been kept the same, the example, the same age, the
same policy term, the same insurance cover of Rs 1 crore. If it has happened, then here you
see in one crore, the premium is coming to ₹ 36000. If you want to take it in lump sum,
if you want to take a discount of Rs. 15, then
the premium will be Rs. 31000. If you give a discount of Rs. 20, then the premium will be Rs. 29000. If you give
a discount of Rs. 30 then the premium is Rs. 25000.
After making the premium for 10 years, you are getting Rs. 040. After the % discount, if you buy Rs.
14000 for Rs. 60, then after paying Rs. 000 premium, you will get Rs. 1 crore. Insurance is covered
for the next 30 years and here you take 50 lakhs together, if you
want to take 50 lakhs in monthly installments, then there also you get a discount of 75 on 10 and 15. The
third option is available. If you don't want to take 2 crores or 1 crore, 50
lakhs or you think that much is enough, I can afford the premium or
insurance cover, you have to take only this much, in that case also you
are getting the cover of 50 lakhs in 22232 only. You have to pay the premium only for 10 years and if you
apply the discount then it will go up to Rs. 000. If you get the % discount then you have to
pay Rs. 155 563 only for 10 years and you will get an insurance cover of Rs. 50 lakh
for the next 30 years and if you see it in regular pay then Only you will see that you will get up to Rs 814, there
is also an option of end pay till Rs 60, take Rs 25 lakh in lump sum and the remaining Rs 25 in installments, if you
take it as monthly income then you will get benefit there also, so
this one. The option is the best option. Company lunched by ICIC Provincial, so
you can utilize it as per your need. If you liked the video, then my
video is available on more than youtube3, you can go there and
explore more insurance products. Thank you. You so much Jai
Hind
i